Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/wolfgang-lochner-b803a5 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Requirements Analysis Software Product Management Product Strategy

Languages

English (Professional Working) German (Native or Bilingual)

Patents

Network location service SELF-CONFIGURING NETWORK

Wolfgang Lochner

Director, Product Management / Principal Product Manager San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

20+ years product line management in the security / networking infrastructure, software and cloud industries with extensive international experience. Background in Product Marketing, Sales Engineering, Software development.

Switching, Firewalls, VPN, WAN connectivity and WAN acceleration, Single Sign-On and Identitity and Access Management (IAM), Network Services (DNS / DHCP), Analytics and Reporting, Centralized Management, Embedded Systems / IoT.

Specialties: networking protocols and security, operating systems, network management software, reporting and analytics, physical and virtual appliances, Cloud, product lifecycle policies and processes.

Experience

Inseego Corp

Director of Product Management, Enterprise Solutions July 2021 - October 2022 (1 year 4 months)

United States

- Product Management Lead for Inseego's new Enterprise 5G SD EDGE
 Solution. Brought the solution from a technology concept to product. This product line consists of 5G Modems and Routers on-premises, a cloud-based router as well as a ZTNA security gateway and centralized management for zero touch provisioning and monitoring of the infrastructure, running in private or public cloud, integrating with other solutions with northbound interfaces.
- Product Management for Inseego's flagship 5G cellular network router, used for secure site to site use cases

Pulse Secure

Sr. Director Product Management / Distinguished Product Manager, Secure Access Solutions

June 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 4 months)

San Jose, California

- Product Management Lead for PCS (VPN, VDI Gateway and Single Sign On / IAM), PPS (Network Access Control, device profiling RADIUS Server), vADC Application Delivery Controller and Pulse One (Centralized Management and Analytics SaaS product).
- Manager of four Product Managers. Hired one additional Product Manager, mentor for Interns.
- Individual contributor for vADC (Local and Global Traffic Management / Load Balancing, Web Application Firewall (WAF)
- Individual contributor for appliances hardware, platform software and certifications (FIPS, Common Criteria, JTIC, SOC 2)
- Owner of Product Management processes and policies. Developed and introduced a new software release and support policy to offer Long Term Support releases in a way that did not require additional resources
- Advisor to new Analytics SaaS offering for SSL VPN and Zero Trust Network Access

Riverbed Technology

Director, Product Management, WAN Optimization January 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 2 months) Sunnyvale, CA

- Introduced WAN-OPT centralized management and analytics into the cloud, starting with Azure and AWS
- Created a strategy to unify WAN-OPT and SD-WAN centralized management and analytics platforms for increased user experience
- Introduced new pricing and licensing strategy with software focus, offering perpetual and subscription pricing, consistent between cloud, virtual and a physical new generation of WAN Optimization appliances
- Defined requirements for WAN-OPT networking and security features (QoS, path selection, SAML for management, ...)

F5 Networks

Sr. Product Manager, Application Delivery Controller - Access Security May 2015 - September 2017 (2 years 5 months)

San Jose, California, United States

- Product Manager for F5's ADC Access Policy Manager (APM), managing Identity and Access Management (IAM) features including OAuth, SAML and integrations with IAM vendors (Okta, Ping Identity, VMware, Microsoft,...)
- Defined features using an Agile methodology, working closely with 30+ customers to analyze use cases to prioritize Agile sprint content. GTM planning and material creation, internal, external and with the partners.

- Product Manager for F5's VDI proxy integrations with Citrix, Microsoft and VMware. Defined and synced roadmap.
- Product Manager for F5's centralized management and analytics solution for all of the Access Security functionality.
- Defined pricing for new generation as well as new higher scaling models of physical and virtual APM appliances.

Infoblox

Sr. Product Manager, Appliance Platforms and Reporting June 2010 - April 2015 (4 years 11 months)

Santa Clara, CA

- •• Product Manager for Infoblox' physical and virtual appliances for Network Services (DNS, DHCP, IP Address Management), Network Automation, DDoS, and Reporting / Analytics, reporting to VP of Product Management.
- Defined reports and analytics / threat prevention requirements for DNS and DHCP anomalies and attacks. Defined APIs using REST and data export capabilities for integration with partner solutions
- Proposed to the Executive Team a next generation of appliances for all product lines during IPO of Infoblox.
- Introduced the products with significant additional hardware and software features, enabling entering the Service Provider / Carrier market, leading to incremental multi-million \$ per quarter revenue, and increasing competitive advantages for the Enterprise market.
- Introduced a new small appliance and virtual appliances for local survivability for branch offices such as Retail, Hospital and Government deployments.

 Product introduction closed a \$2+M opportunity.
- Established and ran a core team to monitor adoption and quality of the new hardware generation
- Partnership Management: Worked closely with Splunk used in the Infoblox Analytics product, and for virtual appliances with Cisco, Riverbed, VMware to identify new capabilities and align roadmaps.

Check Point Software Technologies

Product Manager, Security Gateway Software Infrastructure and Virtualization

September 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 9 months)

Redwood City, CA

 Product Management for Check Point's operating systems for the Security Gateway / NG Firewall appliances (Check Point SPLAT, Nokia IPSO – acquired by Check Point): Developed a proposal to unify the two operating systems in a phased approach. Collected customer, channel partner and field feedback. Developed GTM plan and material.

- Product Management for Check Point's virtualized security appliances for managed service providers (VSX software and VSX-1 appliances), as well as virtual machine / cloud based appliances (VE). Led VMware integration.
- Product Manager for FIPS and EAL-4+ Common Criteria certifications

Extreme Networks

Sr. Product Manager, Operating System + Network Management August 2001 - August 2008 (7 years 1 month) Santa Clara, CA

- Product Management and Product Marketing for Extreme Networks' L2 / L3
 Ethernet switch OS and Network Management / Analytics products, reporting to the Sr. VP Product Management
- Introduced a next generation operating system (SOAP APIs, scriptable CLI, automatic port configuration, modern web management, IPv6,...), "ExtremeXOS". Managed transition, working closely with key Enterprise and Service Provider customers to prioritize feature sets. Introduced now patented features for analytics and provisioning.
- Hired and managed two Product Managers. Retained individual contributor responsibility for ExtremeXOS
- Responsible for all external and internal collateral for the OS and management software. Evangelist at industry events such as IPv6 Summit and trade shows. Presenter at regular channel and customer events.
- Established a formal software release policy and process. Certified internal auditor for ISO 9001 and TL 9000.
- Partnership Management: Worked closely with partners (Avaya for VoIP, Juniper for RADIUS, NetScout for RMON, InMon for sFlow, ...) on feature integration and compatibility testing

Wind River Systems, Inc Product Manager, Sales Engineer, Development Manager February 1991 - July 2001 (10 years 6 months) Sunnyvale, CA

- Marketing Manager, Automotive / Telematics, Sunnyvale, CA, USA2/2000 7/2001
- o SDK market strategy and product definition (OS / OSEK, communication protocols (CAN, J1850, MOST, Bluetooth, ...), User Interface graphics and device drivers. Drove a third-party program / ecosystem to build a vertical market solution

- Product Marketing Manager, Networking, Sunnyvale, CA, USA3/1998 2/2000
- o Product Management and Product Marketing for embedded portable IPv4/ IPv6 TCP/IP stacks, SNMP stack, RMON stack, RIP/OSPF/BGP/DVMRP/PIM routing stacks, HTTP stack. Products could be ported to any OS.
- Sr. Field Application Engineer, Asia/Pacific (Japan/Korea/Taiwan/China),
 Sunnyvale, CA, USA3/1997 3/1998
- Field Application Engineer, US Western Region, Sunnyvale, CA, USA 3/1996
 3/1997
- Manager of Development and Pre-/Post-Sales Support, 10 person startup in Munich Germany – acquired 1996 2/1991 – 3/1996
- o Manager of 3 engineers and individual contributor
- o Development of bring-up code and device drivers for the embedded operating system
- o Sales Systems Engineering and Technical Marketing. Articles for magazines, presentations at public technology events and customer visits, product demos.
- o Technical Support for development tools, embedded OS / SDK and custom developed software

Education

Technical University of Munich

Master of Science (Dipl. Ing, Univ), Electrical Engineering and Information Technology · (1984 - 1990)